https://www.sportsshoes.com/support/privacy/

HomeChristmas
Mens
Mens
Mens StoreSport
SportRunningOutdoorsGymTennisBikingSwimmingTriathlonSquashClimbingHockeyWeightliftingShop AllShoes
ShoesRoadTrail / FellTrack & FieldWalkingSandalsGymCourtShop AllClothing
ClothingJacketsTopsT-ShirtsVestsTightsBottomsShortsCompressionHi-VizSocksShop AllAccessories
AccessoriesGPS & WatchesHydrationInjury AccessoriesGlovesHatsSocksTop Brands
Top BrandsASICSNikeADIDASUnder ArmourHoka One OneSalomonMontaneNew BalanceMizunoInov-8Merrell
Womens
Womens
Womens StoreSport
SportRunningOutdoorsGymTennisSwimmingTriathlonYogaNetballClimbingHockeyShop AllShoes
ShoesRoadTrail / FellTrack & FieldWalkingSandalsGymCourtShop AllClothing
ClothingJacketsTopsT-ShirtsVestsBra / Support TopsShortsTightsBottomsCompressionHi-VizShop AllAccessories
AccessoriesSocksHatsGlovesInjury AccessoriesGPS & WatchesHydrationTop Brands
Top BrandsASICSNikeADIDASHoka One OneNew BalanceSalomonMontaneUnder ArmourMizunoInov-8Merrell
Junior
Junior
Junior StoreSport
SportRunningOutdoorsTennisHandballHockeyCricketSquashBadmintonTriathlonProduct Type
Product TypeShoesSandalsJacketsTopsT-ShirtsShortsBottomsSocksCompressionAccessoriesTop Brands
Top BrandsASICSADIDASSkechersKeenRegattaVivoBarefootMerrellMizunoSalomonSauconyUnder Armour
Run
Run
Run StoreGender
GenderMensWomensJuniorShoes
ShoesRoad- Cushioned- Support- Racing- BarefootTrailTrack & FieldCross CountrySocksShop AllClothing
ClothingJacketsTopsT-ShirtsVestsBra / Support TopShortsTightsBottomsHigh VisibilityShop AllAccessories
AccessoriesSocksHydration & BottlesHeadwear & HatsGlovesFoam RollersInjury AccessoriesSleevesHeadlampsSunglassesShop AllTop Brands
Top BrandsASICSNikeHoka One OneADIDASSalomonInov-8New BalanceMizunoUnder ArmourRonHill
Gym
Gym
Gym StoreGender
GenderMensWomensJuniorShoes
ShoesTraining / FitnessWeightliftingBoxingSocksShop AllApparel
Apparel JacketsTopsT-ShirtsVestsBra / Support TopUnderwearShortsTightsBottomsCompressionShop AllAccessories
AccessoriesSocksBottlesBagsInjury SupportsFoam RollersKinesiology TapeGlovesHeadwearHeadphonesWatchesShop AllTop Brands
Top BrandsNikeUnder ArmourReebokInov-8ADIDASMizunoShock AbsorberNew BalanceASICSStanceShop All
Hike
Hike
Hike StoreGender
GenderMensWomensJuniorShoes
ShoesWalking ShoesWalking BootsSandalsMinimalistSocksShop AllClothing
ClothingJackets- Down Jackets- Waterproof Jackets- Gilets- Shop All JacketsTopsT-ShirtsShortsBottomsUnderwearShop AllAccessories
AccessoriesBackpacksGlovesGPS & WatchesHeadlampsHeadwearHydration & BottlesPolesSleeping BagsSunglassesShop AllTop Brands
Top BrandsAdidas TerrexBerghausHaglofsGore-TexKeenMerrellMontaneMountain HardwearSalomonTevaView All
Brands
Brands
View All BrandsADIDASASICSHoka One OneInov-8MizunoMontaneNew BalanceNikeSalomonSauconyUnder Armour
Sports
Sports
RunningGym HikeTriathlonSwimrunWeightliftingBikingHockeyNetballSquashTennisBadmintonHandballBasketballCricketSwimmingBoxingClimbingYogaSpecialist Stores
Specialist StoresThe Trail StoreThe Compression StoreThe Triathlon StoreThe Swimrun StoreTrack and Field StoreThe Sandals StoreThe Injury StoreThe Sock StoreThe Gore Fabrics StoreThe Climbing StoreThe Biking Store
Advice
The Running Hub
The Training Hub
The Trail Hub
The Hiking Hub
Latest Articles
Inspirational Trails 11: Creag BheagInspirational Trails 10: Slieve CroobInspirational Trails 9: The Jurassic CoastInspirational Trails 9: The Jurassic Coast
Online Gait Analysis
Running Shoe Finder
Wet Footprint Test Video
Jacket Finder
At Home Workouts
Marathon Guide
Great Run Local
Advice
Sale
Sale
Sale StoreThe Sale Store
The Sale StoreMens SaleWomens SaleJunior SaleShoe SaleClothing SaleBy Sport
By SportRunningOutdoorGymTennisTriathlonSwimmingBikingBy Price
By Price£0 - £20£20 - £40£40 - £60£60 - £80£80+By Discount
By DiscountOver 40% OffOver 50% OffOver 60% OffOver 70% Off
Language
English
English
Deutsch
Español
Francais
Italiano
Currency
£
€
US$
AU$
DKK(kr)
NOK(kr)
SEK(kr)
Help & Information
My Account
Create Account
Track Order
Delivery
&			 Returns
Catalogue
Secure Shopping
Our Privacy Promise
What Kind of Personal Information Do We Collect?
The Legal Bases for Using Your Personal Information
When Do We Collect Your Data?
How and Why We Use Your Personal Data
Sharing Your Data with Third Parties
How We Protect Your Data
Where Your Data May be Stored and Processed
How Long Do We Keep Your Data?
Your Rights Relating to Your Data
Privacy of Children On Our Website
Changes to Our Privacy Statement
Contact Us
OUR PRIVACY PROMISE
We want to put you in the driving seat when it comes to your data and it’s important to us that you have absolute confidence in how we look after your personal information.
We are committed to managing your personal information with great care and in accordance with the high standards required by data protection legislation including the General Data Protection Regulation and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations.
We respect your right to privacy and your right to understand and control how your personal data is used. We do not and will not sell your data to third parties and will always keep it safe and secure.
Our Privacy Statement sets out the data we will collect from you, how we use it, and how you can exercise your rights in relation to your data.
What Kind of Personal Information Do We Collect?
Information You Provide Yourself
We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us including:
Name
Address
Telephone Number
Email
Payment methods
Your order history and shopping preferences
Details of your interactions with our customer service team, for example if you contact us about your delivery, to change your details or to give us feedback, including details of any comments or conversations via telephone, email, live chat and social platforms
Your marketing preferences
Your product and service reviews
Your identifier on social channels when you contact us via those platforms
Information We Collect Automatically
We collect certain information from you automatically when you use our website including:
Operating system and version
IP address
Your web browser, version and device
We may also collect information about you using cookies. For more information on our Cookies Policy, please click here.
The Legal Bases for Using Your Personal Information
Performance of a Contract
We will use your data to fulfil your order and our contractual obligations to you. For example, we will collect your name and address details and pass them on to our courier to deliver your order to you.
With your Consent
For example, when you actively sign up to receive our newsletter by email or request our Run and Training Books by post via the sign up link on the website. Where we process your personal information on the basis of your consent, you can withdraw that consent at any time.
Legitimate Interests
In certain situations we may use your personal information to pursue our legitimate interests that might reasonably be expected as part of running our business.
We will always balance our legitimate interests against your rights, freedom and interests as an individual. We will only exercise our legitimate interests when this does not materially impact on your rights, freedoms and interests. Where we process your data based on our legitimate interests, you have the right to object at any time.
For example, we may use your contact details to send you direct marketing about similar products and offers which may interest you or use your purchase history to send you personalised and relevant offers. You can unsubscribe from these communications at any time.
Legal Compliance
We may need to collect, process and in some specific situations share your data in order to comply with our legal obligations and regulatory requirements for example in relation to HMRC regulatory requirements or sharing information with Crime Prevention Agencies to prevent fraud.
When Do We Collect Your Data?
When you access our website
When you create an online account
When you place an order with us on the website or on other marketplaces
When you contact us via telephone, email, live chat, post or on social channels
When you actively sign up to receive our newsletter
When you actively sign up to a social promotion
How and Why We Use Your Personal Data
To Deliver Our Service
We will use your name and address and contact details and share these with our courier to process and deliver your order.
We will use your email address to send you service emails such as your order confirmation and delivery updates.
We will store your order history to help us assist you should you need any help with an ongoing or new order, including dates, product and size details, delivery and contact details.
We will store details of any communications you have with us via email, Live Chat, post, social platforms or telephone to enable us to deliver the best possible service and to assist you with any purchases, problems or complaints.
We will do so to fulfil our contractual obligations to you, to comply with regulatory requirements and on the basis of our legitimate interest to deliver the best possible customer service.
For Direct Marketing
From time to time we will send our existing customers details of similar products and offers by email and/or post. We will do so on the basis of our legitimate interest to engage with our customers and grow our business and in accordance with the requirements of Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations. You can opt out of receiving marketing messages from us when you give us your personal information and thereafter at any time. To unsubscribe, please click here, or email us at marketingpreferences@sportsshoes.com.
When you actively sign up and consent to receive our newsletter via our sign up page on the website, we will use your personal information to send you our latest new product releases, news and offers by email. You can withdraw your consent and opt out of receiving our newsletter at any time here.
When you actively request to receive our Running and Training books by post we will collect and store your name and address to despatch these to you.
To Improve Your Experience
Information We Collect When You Access the Site
When you access the website we will automatically collect and analyse certain information to optimise your site experience, including your IP address, language and currency preference, operating system and browser version and device. We will do so on the basis of our legitimate interest in ensuring optimal site functionality and ease of use for website users.
Cookies
This site uses cookies both to optimise your site experience and to provide us with analytics information to help us learn more about how we can improve our site and improve your experience further. For example we may anonymously track how long you spend on the site and which pages you browse. This site uses Google Analytics for anonymous reporting of site usage to help us understand how you use the site. You can learn more about our Cookies Policy here.
Feefo Review Platform
We will contact you after you have placed your order via the review platform, Feefo, to request your feedback on your product and overall experience with us. We will do so on the basis of our legitimate interest to evaluate and improve our service based on customer feedback and may contact you to resolve any issues you have had with our service. You are not under any obligation to provide any feedback. If you choose to do so, you consent to the publication of your feedback on the Feefo review platform and the Sportsshoes.com website. You can choose to make your feedback anonymous if you prefer.
Profiling
We use profiling to get to know our customers better and to personalise our services to help us to only send you messages that are interesting and relevant to you. We do this on the basis of our legitimate interest to understand our business and to tailor our offers and service accordingly – and so that we don’t waste your time with offers and products that aren’t relevant or useful to you. We may make use of additional information about you that is available from external third party sources to help us do this effectively. You have the right to object to profiling for direct marketing purposes at any time and can do so by emailing us at marketingpreferences@sportsshoes.com.
Sharing Your Data with Third Parties
We do not and will not sell your data to third parties.
Where necessary we will share your data with trusted service providers who will process your data on our behalf. For example, we will share your data with our couriers to deliver your order, to our payment providers who will process your payment and screen the transaction for fraud, to our email provider to send emails or with other professional contractors and service providers necessary to run our business. We will share your information with the review platform Feefo, who will contact you on our behalf to request your feedback.
We work closely with our suppliers and service providers to ensure your data is protected and secured according to the high standards required by data protection legislation and the guiding principles of this privacy statement. Our service providers:
May only process your data strictly for the exact purpose specified by us.
Will only receive the minimum personal information required to perform that function.
Must secure your data in accordance with data protection legislative requirements.
Must delete or anonymise all data should we cease to use their service, subject to regulatory requirements.
Are subject to the same standards contained in this privacy statement.
How We Protect Your Data
The security of your data is of the utmost important to us and we take the protection of your personal information seriously.
We use physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to secure your data when stored and transmitted. These include modern data encryption, firewalls alongside other security devices - as well as strict internal security procedures to protect your personal information. We may at times ask you to verify your identity as part of our security procedure.
Where you have registered for a SportsShoes.com online account, it is important to protect against unauthorised access to it by keeping your password safe and logging off when you complete your session.
Where Your Data May be Stored and Processed
Sometimes we may need to store or transfer your data to third party suppliers in countries outside of the European Economic Area. Where we do so, we take great care in ensuring your personal information is protected and secured to the same high standards and with the same safeguards as though it was being stored or processed inside the EEA, for example by using standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission.
How Long Do We Keep Your Data?
We will store your personal data for as long as you have an account with us or as long as it is necessary to provide our service, resolve disputes, comply with regulatory requirements and otherwise necessary to allow us to conduct our business. If you have a question about specific retention periods for certain types of personal information, please email us at dataprotection@sportsshoes.com .
Your Rights Relating to Your Data
It’s important to us that when it comes to your data that you understand and can control how we use your personal information. You have and may exercise the following rights in relation to how we use your data.
The right to know how your data is used by us - as set out in this privacy statement.
The right to access your data. You have the right to request of a copy of the data we hold about you. You can do so by emailing us at dataprotection@sportsshoes.com We will respond to a request to access your data within 28 days.
The right for the data that we hold about you to be accurate and up to date – and the right to rectify any information we hold about you that is incorrect. You can update your personal information via your online account or by contacting our customer service team at customerservice@sportsshoes.com or on 01274 530530 (international +44 1274 530530)
In some circumstances you can ask us to erase, block or restrict the personal information we hold about you or object to ways in which we are using your personal information. Further, where we are using your personal information on the basis of your consent, you may withdraw that consent at any time. Where we use your personal information based on our legitimate interest, you have the right to object at any time. For help and more information, please contact dataprotection@sportsshoes.com
The right to lodge a complaint with your Data Protection Regulator. In the UK, this is the Information Commissioner’s Office http://www.ico.org.uk/concerns
Privacy of Children On Our Website
Our website is not intended for use by children under the age of 18. We will not knowingly collect any data from any person below the age of 18.
Changes to Our Privacy Statement
We may modify or update this statement from time to time to ensure compliance with new data protection legislation and where necessary to reflect changes in policy or customer feedback. Where there are important changes to this policy we will notify you via a notice on our website. We recommend that you review this statement regularly to learn more about how we are using your information.
Contact Us
B-Sporting Ltd, trading as Sportsshoes.com, registered Company No. 1627024 is the Data Controller when you access our website or use our service. If you:
Have any questions or concerns about how we use your data.
Would like to exercise your rights as set out above.
Would like to make a complaint or give us feedback regarding our privacy policy.
Please contact us at dataprotection@sportsshoes.com or write to us at Data Protection, Sportsshoes.com, 1 The Park, Jubilee Way, Shipley, BD18 1QG.
Please wait while we authorise your payment.
Please wait...
Sorry, there was an error with PayPal, please try again later or alternatively use another payment method.
Live Chat
Loading...
